SHARL SHERIF

Nasr City, Cairo, Egypt 11511 • 0-114-146-1405 • dev.sharl.sherif@gmail.com

sharlsherif.github.io • https://www.linkedin.com/in/sharl-sherif1/ • github.com/sharlsherif

Professional Summary

Experienced Full Stack Javascript Developer with over 2 years of experience in Web Development. Excellent reputation for resolving problems, improving customer satisfaction, and driving overall operational improvements. Consistently saved costs while increasing profits.

Skills

- React. js & Redux
- Javascript ES5/ES6
- GraphQL & REST APIs
- Node.js (Express)

- Websockets (Socket.io)
- MongoDB & Firebase
- MySQL & SQL Server

Work History

Backend Developer (Nodejs-MongoDB), 06/2019 to Current

Azdan Business Analytics - Egypt, Cairo

- · Represented web team at meetings with executives and discussed project goals and milestones.
- Analyzed requirements and designed, developed and implemented software applications on the assigned project.
- · Tested the web application and performed troubleshooting prior to deployment.
- Used programming capabilities in JavaScript, MongoDB and other technologies as needed.
- · Worked effectively in a Scrum team.
- Applied agile methodology to shorten cycle time and achieve target margins.

Full Stack Javascript Developer, 11/2018 to Current

Upwork - Egypt, Cairo

- · Tracked hours and expenses for each project, detailing each action and charge.
- · Submitted professional proposals and project scopes to potential employers.
- Developed network of related professionals to open up business opportunities.
- Performed work according to project schedules and high quality standards.
- Hired, trained, and provided daily direction for 7 employees.
- Managed creative projects from concept to completion while managing outside vendors.

Full Stack Web Developer, 06/2019 to 11/2019

Cubezy - Egypt, Cairo

- Automated a time consuming process of data entry
- Adjusted software parameters to boost performance and incorporate new features.
- Consulted with engineering team members to determine system loads and develop improvement plans.
- Compiled specifications, testing methods and other information for Course Providers project into technical manuals for use in future assignments.

Education

Bachelor of Science: Management Information Systems

Modern Academy In Maadi - Bein Al Ganayen, Cairo Governorate